We are no longer in control.
Blackhat is a crime, thriller, action film directed by Michael Mann.
Nicholas Hathaway, a furloughed convict, and his American and Chinese partners hunt a
high-level cybercrime network from Chicago to Los Angeles to Hong Kong to Jakarta.
As Hathaway closes in, the stakes become personal as he discovers that the
attack on a Chinese nuclear power plant was just the beginning.
Nicholas Hathaway, played by Chris Hemsworth.
Chen Lien, played by Tang Wei.
Chen Dawai, played by Leehom Wang.
Carol Barrett, played by Viola Davis.
Mark Jessup, played by Holt McCallany.
Alex Trang, played by Andy On Chi-Kit.
Blackhat is a 2015 American action thriller film produced and directed by Michael Mann, written by
Morgan Davis Foehl, and starring Chris Hemsworth, Tang Wei, Viola Davis, and Wang Leehom.
Hemsworth portrays a convicted hacker offered clemency for
helping track down a dangerous cybercriminal.
The title refers to the cybersecurity term "black hat,"
meaning a hacker with malicious intent.
The film premiered at the TCL Chinese Theatre in Los Angeles on January 8, 2015,
and was released in theaters on January 16, by Universal Pictures.
Blackhat was a box-office bomb, earning only $19.7 million at
the box office against a budget of $70 million.
The film received generally mixed reviews, with criticisms focused on casting and
pace, though the film appeared on some critics' year-end lists.
A re-edited director's cut of the film was
released on home video in November 2023.
The film explores themes of race against time,
computer, hacker, computer virus, technology.
The tone is intense.